Jessica Michelle Farias Rosado

Mechatronic Engineer & Full-Stack Web Developer

Website: https://jessicafarias.github.io/ | GitHub: jessicafarias | LinkedIn: jessica-michelle-farias-rosado

SUMMARY

Fascinated by the innovation and technological advancement that my generation has lived through, five years ago I decided to study Mechatronic Engineering. Upon graduation, I decided to specialize in programming, so I applied to Microverse and thus define my career as a Full-Stack Web Developer.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5,

CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL **Design:** Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator | Canva

Styling: SASS | CSS-in-JS | Bootstrap

Mobile development: Java

Desktop development: C#

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD,

Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork,

Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Month, Year - Present

Talkey social network— This website has the basic functionalities of a social network similar to Twitter, but it uses a different interface.

• Built with: Ruby on Rails | SQL | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Git | Eslint | Jest

RPG Game — This project is a role-playing game. The project works with asynchronous functions to POST and GET data from a JSON file.

• Built with: JavaScript | Webpack | Git | Phaser3 | Eslint | Jest

Weather forecast — Search for a specific location and display the weather there in Fahrenheit or Celsius. Designed to be an interactive and responsive website.

Built with: JavaScript HTML | CSS | Webpack | Git | Phaser3 | Eslint | Jest |

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) May, 2020 – Jan, 2021

Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

ENERKI Mérida, México
Position Title Sep, 2018 – May, 2019

- Designed projects and coordinated the team
- Programmed two CNC machines: a milling machine and a plasma machine
- Attended special courses to control PLCs.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE April, 2020 – Jan, 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 2000+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY AUTONOMOUS OF YUCATAN

Jan, 2012 - Jan, 2019

Mechatronic engineer

- Developed mobile and desktop applications using Visual Studio and PostgreSQL and AndroidStudio.
- Worked with a variety of languages for devices such as micro-controllers or PLCs
- Worked with both local hosting and cloud storage